<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
  <title>Getting Started</title>

  <para>This chapter will introduce you to the CUAE SDK, its relationship with
  Microsoft .NET, and explore the Cisco Unified Application Designer. After
  reading this chapter and following the instructions contained within it you
  should have a functioning CUAE development environment.</para>

  <section>
    <title>CUAE Development Environment Prerequisites</title>

    <para>The CUAE depends on several external frameworks and applications to
    do its job. The main components of CUAE are programmed using a combination
    of C#, Java, and C++. The Application Server is the component that
    directly affects developers and it is developed using C#. This means that
    many of the programmatic interfaces are accessed via C#; therefore, a .NET
    development environment is required to start using the CUAE.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Installing the .NET Framework SDK and Friends</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Mono vs. the Microsoft .NET Framework</title>

      <para>As of CUAE version 2.4 only Microsoft .NET is officially
      supported. Developers may wish to use Mono when building plug-ins. While
      this has not explicitly been tested it is possible that it may work.
      Mono will produce binary compatible assemblies when building in release
      mode. Your mileage may vary, but adventurous developers may find success
      if they want to experiment with the Mono implementation of .NET.</para>

      <para>The Application Server will always need to be executed using the
      Microsoft CLR. There are third-party libraries that we leverage that
      will not run under Mono. Only use Mono for building plug-in assemblies
      and not for running the Application Server software.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Installing the CUAE SDK</title>

      <para></para>

      <section>
        <title>Operating System Requirements</title>

        <para></para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Downloading and Installing the SDK</title>

        <para></para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>VMWare Components in the Absence of Communications
        Manager</title>

        <para></para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>The Relationship Between CUAE and .NET</title>

    <para></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Getting to Know the Application Designer</title>

    <para>The Application Designer is the primary development interface of the
    CUAE. It is an interactive development environment that enables you to
    build a unified communications application visually and in a workflow type
    manner. The goal of the Application Designer is to make building the
    communications portion of your application very easy. It is tightly
    integrated with the Application Server to enable you to quickly build,
    deploy, and debug your applications. In this section we will take a brief
    visual tour of the Application Designer before getting into more detail on
    how to use it in later chapters.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Explorer, Canvas, Property Grid and Toolbox</title>

      <para>Blah blah</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Annotated Application Designer Main Window</title>

        <screenshot>
          <screeninfo>Annotated Application Designer Main Window</screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="supplements/images/designer-annotated.png" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Global vs. Function Canvas</title>

      <para>The global canvas</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Application Designer Global Canvas</title>

        <screenshot>
          <screeninfo>Application Designer Global Canvas</screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="supplements/images/designer-global-canvas.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>

      <para>Function canvas</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Application Designer Function Canvas</title>

        <screenshot>
          <screeninfo>Application Designer Function Canvas</screeninfo>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="supplements/images/designer-function-canvas.png"
                         format="PNG" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </screenshot>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>